Guide to the Raul Salinas Papers, ca. 1950-1994
Department of Special Collections
- Series 8: Secondary Literature on Raul Salinas
  - Salinas, Raul R. Offprints of "Homenaje al Pachuco," "Los Barios de Aztlan," "Quasi-Elegaic," and "Journey II." n.d. (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Salinas, Raul R. Indio Trails. Red Salmon Press, 1985. [Front cover of publication only] 1985 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Salinas, Raul R [?]. "Love/War," 1975. 1975 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Salinas, Raul R. Poesia Chicana, Limited Edition, 1981. 1981 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Salinas, Raul R. A Trip through the Mind Jail. [Script for performance of poem?] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Salinas, Raul R. "Unity Vision," n.d. n.d. (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Salinas, Raul R. Viaje/Trip. Hellcoal Press, 1973. [First edition] 1973 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Si Se Puede, Vol. 5, no. 3. n.d. (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Street Talk, 1973 Sept. 10. 1973 Sept. 10 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Student Writings form U.T. Class with Raul Salinas, 1974. 1974 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Sunfighter, n.d. [Includes "Resisting Mind Fuck" by Raul Salinas.] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Tonantzin, Vol. 2, no. 2 (Mar. 1985). 1985 Mar. (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Torres, Luis A. The Poetry of Raul Salinas: A Review Essay, n.d. n.d. (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - "Un Trip through the Mind Jail," unsigned rev., n.d. n.d. (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Tirando Rollo Con Tapon: Toricas informales & interviews ineditos. TMs, n.d. n.d. (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - University of Washington Daily. Articles by Raul Salinas, 1973 Jan. 12- Feb. 1 1973 Jan. 12 -Feb. 1 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Vajito, Vol. 1, no. 1 (Sept 1981). 1981 Sept. (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - The Washington Review, Vol. 1, no. 1 (Nov. 1974). [Includes "Quasi-Elegaic" by Raul Salinas, p. 15.] 1974 Nov. (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Writings, Mentions & Political Activities. [Newspaper clippings] c. 1973 -1981 (Box 27, Folder 35)
- Series 9: Movimiento Publications
  - a. Chicano Literature
    - Aspectos de la Literatura Chicana, 1979. 1979 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - California Women: State of California Report. 1969 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Cantos Rebeldes de las Americas: Teatro Mestizo. 1974 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Chicanismo, Vol. 4, issue 2 (Winter 1973). 1973 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Chicanismo, Vol. 5, issue 1 (Fall 1973). 1973 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Chicano! Oakland. Oakland Public Library, 1970. 1970 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - C.I.R.N.: Colorado Immigration & Refugee Network. 1982 May 29 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - La Confluencia, Vol. 2, no. 4 (1978 Dec.) 1978 Dec. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - La Confuencia, Vol. 3, no. 2 (1979 June). 1979 June (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Citybender, Vol. 1, no. 1 (1977 June). 1977 June (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Citybender, Vol. 1, no. 2 (1977 Aug.). 1977 Aug. (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Citybender, Vol. 2, no. 1 (1978). 1978 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Citybender, Vol. 2, no. 3 (1978). 1978 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Citybender, Vol. 2, no. 4 (1978). 1978 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Citybender, Vol. 2, no. 7 (1978). 1978 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Huehuetitlan, No. 2 (Nov. 1982). 1982 Nov. (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Mass Mobilizations in Mexico. 1982 Jan. 29 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - The Mexican-American: for the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights. 1968 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Mexican-Ameicans & the administration of justice in the southwest, Publication 26. 1970 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Mi Raza Primero. 1976 Apr. 29 -May 1 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Stranger in oneÕs Land: U.S. Commission on Civil Rights Clearing House, Publication no. 19. 1970 May (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Tejano Conjunto Festival. 1983 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - We the Mexican Americans/Nosotros los Mexico Americanos: Bureau of the Census. 1970 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - b. Chicano Literary journals
    - Con Safos, Vol. 1, no. 3 (1968). 1968 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Con Safos, Vol. 1, no. 4. n.d. (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Con Safos, no. 8 (1972). 1972 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Corazon de Aztlan, Vol. 1, no. 1 (1981 Nov.) 1981 Nov. (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Entrelineas, Vol. 1, no. 2 (1971 Feb. - Mar). 1971 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Entrelineas, Vol. 2, nos. 1-2 (1972). 1972 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Entrelineas, Vol. 3, nos. 1-2 (1974). 1974 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - El Fuego de Aztlan, Vol. 1, no. 4 (Summer 1977). 1977 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Metamorfosis, University of Washington, 1977. 1977 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Metamorfosis, Vol. 1, no. 2 (1978). 1978 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Metamorfosis, Vol. 3, no. 2 & Vol. 4, no. 1 (1980-1981). 1980-1981 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Miquiztli, Vol. 1, no. 1 (Fall 1972). 1972 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Miquiztli, Vol. 2, no. 1 (Winter 1974). 1974 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Miquiztli (Winter-Spring 1977). 1977 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - The National Hispanic Journal, Vol. 2, no. 1 (Summer 1983). 1983 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Rasca Tripas (1970 Aug. 29). 1970 Aug. 29 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - La Raza, Vol. 1, no. 7 (1972 Jan.). 1972 Jan. (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - La Raza, Vol. 1, no. 9. n.d. (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - La Raza, Vol. 1, no. 10 (1973 Feb.). 1973 Feb. (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - La Raza, Vol. 1, no. 12 (1973 Sept.). 1973 Sept. (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - La Raza, Vol. 2, no. 1 (1974 Feb.). 1974 Feb. (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - La Raza, Vol. 2, no. 2. n.d. (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Regeneracion, Vol. 1, no. 2 (1970). 1970 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Regeneracion, Vol. 1, no.5 (1970). 1970 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Regeneracion, Vol. 2, no. 3 (1973). 1973 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - El Travieso, Vol. 1, no. 2 (1969 J uly). 1969 July (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - c. Native American journals
    - Arrowhead: Reclaiming Klamath Land, Native American Solidarity Committee, n. d. c. 1976 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Cucaracha, Vol. 8, no. 2 (1983 Feb. 18). 1983 Feb. 18 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - In Support of Indian Fishing Rights, pamphlet, n.d. n.d. (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Johnson, Ralph W. "The States versus Indian Off-Reservation Fishing," Washington Law Review, Vol. 47, no. 2 (1972). 1972 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Miner, Ken. An English-Menominee & Menominee-English Word List, Milwaukee, 1975. 1975 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Pit River Chapter 1 n.d. (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, no. 3. n.d. (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, no. 4. n.d. (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, no. 5. n.d. (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Road to Autonomy: Reverse Discrimination & the Anti-Indian Backlash, Albuquerque, 1978 June. 1978 June (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - La Voz, No. 6 (1979 July). 1979 July (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Wilkinson, Charles F. & Eric R. Biggs, "The Evolution of the Termination Policy," American Indian Law Review, Vol. 5, no. 1. n.d. (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - d. Miscellaneous journals
    - El Aguila 1973 May (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Ahora, Vol. 7, No. 1 n.d. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Antioch College- Juarez Lincoln University n.d. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - The Chicano Struggle and the Struggle for Socialism, Revolutionary Union 1975 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Chicano Studies at Cal State University n. d. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Chicano Theatre, Vol. 3 1974 Spring (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Civil Rights Digest 1970 Winter (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Colegio Jacinto Trevino, Mercedes, Texas n. d. (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Community Relations Service, US Department of Justice n. d. (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Con Safos, Vol. 2, Issue No. 5 1970 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Con Safos, Vol. 2, Issue No. 6 1970 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Los Cuatro n. d. (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - La Cucaracha, Vol. 6, No. 3 1976 May 5 -1981 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - La Cucaracha, Vol. 8, No. 1 1983 Jan. 21 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Las Cucarachas 1974 Summer (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Development Assistance for Rehabilitation, Inc. n. d. (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Entrelineas, Vol. 1, No. 4 1971 June -Sept. (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Garcia Camarillo, Mia; Sacrifice; M & A Editions 1977 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Home Front n. d. (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Jailhouse LawyerÕs Manual, the Prison Law Collective 1973 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - La Lucha del Pueblo, Vol.1, No. 1 1975 July (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Magazin, Vol. 1, No. 2 1971 Nov. (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - El Maizel, Vol. 1, No. 2 n. d. (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Mango, Vol. 1, No. 3 & 4 1977 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Marti, Jose. La Edad de Oro[Havana, 1978] 1889 Sept. (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Los Mejicanos 1975 June 6 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - National Hispanic Journal, Vol. 1, No. 4 1983 Spring (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Newsweek, Vol. 7, No. 26 1976 Feb. (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Performing Arts, Vol. 12, No. 8 1978 Aug. (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - El Poche Che, Vol. 1, No. 3 197? Dec. (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Poetas de Aztlan n. d. (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - La Razon Mestiza, Vol. I, No. 4 1974 Dec. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, No. 1 n. d. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, No.2 n. d. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, No.6 n. d. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, No. 7 n. d. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, No.8 n. d. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, No. 9 n. d. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, No. 10 n. d. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, No. 11 n. d. (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, No. 13 n. d. (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, No. 15 n. d. (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Recobrando, Vol. 1, No. 19 n. d. (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Report of International Jurists Visit with Human Rights Petitioners in the US 1979 Aug. 3-20 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Romano, Octavo Ignacio. The Anthropology and Sociology of Mexican Americans. Reprinted from El Grito, Vol II, No. 1 1968 Fall (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Salinas, Omar. I Go Dreaming Serenades; Mango 1979 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Seattle Acts Festival(Bombershoot)- Literary Acts Announcement 1979 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Sin Cadenas, Vol. 2, No. 4 1975 May (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Son, Riso. Asi Me Uni al Movimiento Obrero, El Comite Central del partido Revolucionario por la Reunificacion 1978 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Teall, Ricardo. There are No Fights Out Tonight; Alberquerque, NM: Pajari to Publications n. d. (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Tin Tan, Vol. 1, No. 1 1975 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Tin Tan, Vol. 1, No. 2 1975 Sept. (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Tonantzin, Vol. 6, No. 3 1990 Oct. (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Tres Colores, Vol. 1, No. 1 1976 May -June (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Vision Northwest, Vol. 1, No. 1 1977 Mar. (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Voces Desde Nicaragua/Voices from Nicaragua; Vol. 1, No. 1 1982 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - La Voz, No. 13 1980 Feb. (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - La Voz 1982 Nov. (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - La Voz 1983 Nov. (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Washington Prisons n. d. (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Ytuarte, Edward & Natividad Cisneros. Alma, Mi Alma Por Vida. Los Angeles: Cal State University Special Services Project n. d. (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - ZOOT SUIT- program n. d. (Box 31, Folder 31)
- Series 10: American Indiam Movement (A.I.M.)
  - El Aviso, Vol. 2, No. 4 1983 Aug. 20 -Sept. 20 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Bennett, Cathy E. [Leonard Peltier Defense Committee] n. d. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Crazy Horse Spirit, No. 3[Leonard Peltier Defense Committee] 1981 Winter -1982 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Geneva; Indigenous People of the Land 1981 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Geneva [United Nations International Indian Treaty Council] 1981 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Geneva; WIZA, Nos. 27-28 1981 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Indian-Chicano Graduate Studies n. d. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - ISHI- the Movie, Press Release 1984 Aug. 22 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Nicaragua [1 of 2] n. d. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Nicaragua[2 of 2] n. d. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Nicaragua: International Indian Treaty [1 of 3] 1981 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Nicaragua: International Indian Treaty [2 of 3] 1981 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Nicaragua: International Indian Treaty [3 of 3] 1981 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Peltier, Lenoard. "Fast for Life", San Antonio; Marion, Mexico n. d. (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Seattle Indian Health Board [plastic card] n. d. (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Southwest Airlines Plane ticket n. d. (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Trejo, Delma and Jim Clark. The American Indian n. d. (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Treaty of Guadalupe Project: Chicano Human Rights Council and I. I. T.C. [1 of 2] 1987 Oct. (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Treaty of Guadalupe Project: Chicano Human Rights Council and I. I. T. C. [2 of 2] n. d. (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Treaty of Guadalupe [folder marked Alianza- what-where-why] n. d. (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Treaty of Guadalupe Project 1988 June 11 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - United Nations Commission on Human Rights 1987 Aug. 10 -Sept. 4 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Alternative Views News Magazine. "Civil Liberties and the Native American." 1980 Summer (Box 33, Folder 1)
    1 videocassette (59 min.)
  - Uranium Factor. ABC Documentary. n.d. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Turnabout. Peltier. Includes part of interview with Indian poet Roy [?] Hardgrove. KTV1 news department. 1986 June 15 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Survival of American Indians. Portland Chapter. Columbus Day, 1975 1975 Oct. 14 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Mis Amigos II. Interview with Bill Means 1984 June (Box 33, Folder 5)
    1 vidoecassette (26 min.)
  - Mis Amigos II. Winona Laduke. 1984 Sept. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    1 videocassette (30 min.)
  - Interview with Margaret Gold. 1985 June 1 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Artistas Indigenas. Remote #4. L.P.S.G. Brunch & Resistencia Bookstore. n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1)
- Series 11: Artifacts
  This series is currently being processed. Access to these materials will be restricted until processing can be completed. For further information, please contact the Manuscripts Processing Librarian of the Department of Special Collections.
- Series 12: Oversized Items
  - a. Oversize publications
    This subseries is currently being processed. Access to these materials will be restricted until processing can be completed. For further information, please contact the Manuscripts Processing Librarian of the Department of Special Collections.
  - b. Oversize broadsides and posters
- Series 13: First Editions
Bibliography
Manuscripts
Notebook with "Contemplation Breeds" poem, ms. 1962.
"East of the Freeway: Reflections de Mi Pueblo." Poems and fragments, ms.
"East of the Freeway: Reflections de Mi Pueblo." Original ts.
"East of the Freeway: Reflections de Mi Pueblo." Draft #3, ts.
"El Embruje de mi Tio Juan." Unpublished collection of short stories, ts.
"Indio Trails." Unpublished collection of poems, ms.
"Mural Destruction Painful Loss for Chicanos," ts.
"Music for the Masses." Unpublished collection of fiction and poetry, ts.
"Poemas en Espanol." Unpublished collection of poems, ms.
"Poemas en Espanol." Unpublished collection of poems, ts.
"Portrait of an Artist," ts.
"Prison Journals." Unpublished journals, ms and ts.
"Un Trip Through the Mind Jail y Otras Excursions." Poems and fragments, ms.
"Un Trip Through the Mind Jail y Otras Excursions." Unedited notebook, ts.
"Un Trip Through the Mind Jail y Otras Excursions." Edited notebook, ts.
"Tu Mujer." Unpublished collection of poems, ts, galleys.
Publications
Books and Chapbooks
[Salinas, Raul, et. al.] "Brainwashing Techniques in Prison." Marion, IL, 1972.
Viaje/Trip. Providence, Rhode Island: Hellcoal Press, 1973.
Un Trip Through the Mind Jail y Otras Excursions. San Francisco: Pocho Che, 1980.
East of the Freeway: Reflections de mi Pueblo. Austin: Red Salmon Press, 1994
"A Trip Through the Mind Jail." In Aztlan: An Anthology of Mexican-American Writings. Ed. Stan Steiner and Luis Valdez. Vintage Press, 1972.
Selected poems in Literatura Chicana: Texto y Contexto. Ed. Antonia Castaneda-Shular, Tomas Ybarra and Joseph Sommers. New York: Prentice-Hall, 1972.
Selected poems in We Are Chicanos. Ed. Philip Ortego. Washington Square Press, 1973.
"Journey II." Voices of Azlan. Eds. Dorothy Harth and Louis Baldwin. New York: Mentor, 1973. pp. 192-96.
"Sinfonia serana." Chicano Voices. Eds. Carlota Cardenas-Dwyer and Tino Villanueva. New York: Houghton-Mifflin, 1975. pp. 133-35.
Selected poems in Time to Greez!: Incantations of the Third World. Ed. Janice Mirikitani and Roberto Vargas. San Francisco: Glide Publishing Company, 1974.
Magazines
Salinas, Raul. "The Quarter Notes," (monthly Jazz column). The ECHO. Huntsville, TX, 1963-1965.
"Portrait of an Artist." Entrelineas. Vols. 5 & 6. (1970).
"Some notes on Semantics in the Joint." Entrelineas. 1. 1 (1970).
"A trip through the mind jail." Aztlan de Leavenworth. 1. 1 (May, 1970).
"Nueva estrella en el horizonte." Aztlan de Leavenworth. 1. 1 (May, 1970).
A trip through the mind jail." Caracol. (1970).
"Nueva estrella en el horizonte." La Raza. 1.2 (1970): 79.
"A Trip Through the Mind Jail." La Raza. 1.2 (1970): 80.
"Los Caudillos." La Raza. 1.4 (Jan 1971): 49.
"Pa' un coco: ciego/sordo/mudo." La Raza. 1.5 (1971): 49.
"The Poetry of Radi Salinas." Magazin. 1. 1 (Oct., 1971): 24-26.
"Portrait of an Artist." Entrelineas. 1.5-6 (Oct.-Dec., 1971): 3-5.
"Muse Moving Mountain;" "Pesadilla." Caracol. (Nov., 1975).
"Homenaje al Pachuco;" "Sinfonia serana;" "el tecato." Tejidos 2.7 (Fall 1975): 5-9.
"Love/War [a metamorphosis of sorts]." Metamorfosis. 1. 1 (Spring, 1977): 17.
[Raul Salinas and Yvonne Yarbro-Bejarano]. "Teatro Review of Short Eyes." Metamorfosis. 2.1-2 (Summer, 1979): 26-35.
"Un trip through the mindjail." Kite: A magazine of prison writings, 1981.
"Mural Destruction Painful Loss for Chicanos.' El Aviso. Jun.-Jul. 1982.
Studies on Salinas
Interviews
Binder, Wolfgang. "Anglos are Weird People for Me": Interviews with Chicanos and Puerto Ricans. Berlin: John F. Kennedy Institute Fur Nordamerikastudien, Freic Universitat, 1979.
"Interview with Raul Salinas." Partial Autobiographies: Interviews with 20 Writers. Ed. W.B. Erlagen. W. Germany: Verlag, Palm, and Erke, 1985.
"Clasico of the Month: Raul (Tapon) Salinas." The Vajito Interview. Sept. 1981.
Ybarro-Frausto, Tomas. "Tirando Rollo con Tapon: Toricas infonnales & Interviews ineditos." 1973.
Mendoza, Louis. "Re-Reading the Body: The Cultural Poetics and Politics of Pinto Art." Cristina Ibarra, videographer. Austin: 1993.
Reviews
Roderick, Rod. Review of Un Trip through the Mind Jail y Otras Excursiones, by Raul Salinas. The Pawn Review. n.d.
Herndon, John. "Intimacies of the Ear." Duende Magazine. Sept. 1988.
Cardenas, Reyes. Review of Un Trip Through the Mind Jail. Caracol. (1976).
Critical Essays
Bruce-Novoa, Juan. "Rescuing the World Center." Chicano Poetry: A Response to Chaos. Austin: University of Texas Press, 1982. pp. 14-47.
Candelaria, Cordelia. Chicano Poeta: A Critical Introduction. Westport, Conn.: Greenwood Press, 1986.
Flores, Lauro. Converging Languages in a World of Conflicts." Visible Language. 21.1 (1987).
Garza, Mario. "Duality in Chicano Poetry." De Colores. 3.4 (1977).
Theses and Presentations
Ericson, David. "Prison Literature and the Question of Genre: The Case of Raul Salinas." Master's Thesis. (Dec 1989, University of Texas at Austin).
Olguin, Ben. "Genealogy of the Pachuco as a Cultural Icon: From Social Pariah to Vernacular Intellectual." Presentation. (Nov 1993, Stanford University).
Serials
Cambon, Glauco. "Raul Salinas: Una Nuova Voce Della Poesia Americana." Annali Di Ca' Foscari 10 (1978).
Cisneros, Sandra. "Los Tejanos: A Testimony to the Silenced." Texas Humanist. Nov. -Dec. 1984. Grajeda, Rafael. "The Pachuco in Chicano Poetry: The Process of Legend Creation." Revista Chicano-Riquena.
Reece, Ray. "Busting Out of the Mind Jail." 1982. [unpublished ms.]
Salas, Abel. "Jazz Jaunts and East Side Haunts: Continuing Conversations with Raul Salinas." [unpublished ms.]
Valdez, Bill. "Raul Salinas Offers Riches of Knowledge." American Statesman. 3 (Nov. 1983).
Literary Dedications
Acosta, Teresa Paloma. "poem sobre raul." Passing Time. Austin: Eakins Press, 1985
Aida. "Raul Salinas"
Algarin, Miguel. "Poema Sexto Sol." Mongo Affair. New York: Nuyorican Press, 1978.
Garcia, Amoldo. "maiztro rafil."
Jimenez, Chuy, "Tapon."
Montoya, Jose. "La Reina Mancornadora." Information: 20 Years of Joda. San Jose: Chusma House, 1992.
Sierra, Ruben. To Raul (El Tapon) Poeta de Aztlan, 1974.
Warren, Charles [Shaka]. "To a Revolutionary Poet From a Revolutionary Poet." Leavenworth Prison, 1971.